# JAMES WOLFE

#### THE BEST CODER

✓ Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com 

<a href="mailto:red">
<a href="mailto:website Portfolio">
<a href="mailto:website Portfolio">
<a href="mailto:website Portfolio">
<a href="mailto:website">
<a

#### **SUMMARY**

Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving and learning, demonstrated experience in programming and customer service. Developed technical skill sets required to thrive in a professional work environment, AWS Cloud, web development, Linux, and computer technology troubleshooting.

## **SKILLS**

Computer Troubleshooting
 Joomla & WordPress
 AWS Cloud
 HTML & CSS
 RedHat
 SSH

#### **PROJECTS**

## Portfolios - Database Websites GitHub Repository

- Created and maintained using AWS Cloud services S3 and Route53, Azure Storage Container with respective HTML, CSS, and Java-script.
- Applied Agile best practices to develop the project while also applying and producing new ideas in the process.

### Serverless Application GitHub Repository

• Launched a word processor application on AWS Amplify utilizing Amplify CLI and REST framework with application files maintained and hosted on GitHub repositories and Atom.

#### **Headless Media Center**

- Utilized Volumio after mounting the bootable program to a Raspberry Pi through the Linux based OS and entering Linux commands to connect the Volumio device to the phone application and account.
- Maintained and worked on the device using respective hardware and output the media player through Fender Squier 4 speakers connected using respective audio and power cables.

## **Computer Building and Troubleshooting**

- Researched and budgeted computer hardware components and building the box while diagnosing rising issues with the POST sequence and maintained the software and hardware using compressed air, file clean up, and back-ups.
- Repaired computer related problems after diagnosing hardware issues for peers such as, mis-aligned RAM and reseating components.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Woodworker Sue's Antiques

06/2021 — Present

• After purchasing and finding old and damaged antique furniture and items, I refurbish them utilizing sanding and stanning techniques, then resell the 18th and 19th century antiques in a variety of store locations gaining key and professional skills.

#### Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

11/2020 - 12/2020

Server related issues such as, unable to POST and RAID configurations, and after analyzing the issue I diagnose the software or hardware
reseating components or rebooting the software through Linux and resolve the ticket, I developed technical skills here required to thrive
in a professional work environment.

## Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

06/2018 - 01/2019

• While working in a fast-paced environment and multi-tasking, I managed my time effectively and made use of a step-by-step process taking orders, serving food and drinks, and welcoming new customers to provide the best quality customer service.

## Sale's Associate PetValu

09/2015 - 08/2017

- Faced with nutritional and health related issues for customers pets while working independently, I worked through problems by asking pet related questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve a customer concern and did it effectively by utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.
- Volunteered with Homeward Trails, German Shepherd Rescue, and PetValu by feeding, cleaning, and playing providing comfort and joy for the pets.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

AWS Cloud Practitioner 7BEZSG02PNEEQ83D

Agile Scrum Fundamentals

ude.my/UC-800faeff-a669-4e5b-b802-3cbb834cdd2f

Linux Administration Bootcamp

ude.my/UC-fcd5c324-ad8c-4b70-a83d-b9712cb3b0f8

## **EDUCATION**

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College Computer Science, Assembly Language, and Calculus II 2016-2020